import { SquareRoot, superscript, subscript, BoldText, ItalicText, Fraction, ShortFraction, LongFraction, MixedFraction, Isotopes } from "@/mathnotation"

const path = "@/assets/images/pastquestions-figures/integratedscience/integratedscienceA/integratedscience-"

export const INTEGRATEDSCIENCEA2007 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. Which of the following quantities is not a vector quantity?",
A: "force",
B: "Mass",
C: "Velocity",
D: "weight",
answer: "B. Mass",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. Microbes are useful in the leather industry for",
A: "their use in tanning leather",
B: "beautifying leather products,",
C: "protecting leather against the environment",
D: "providing raw materials to the industry",
answer: "A. their use in tanning leather",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. The inorganic mineral particles of the soil are derived from",
A: "decaying animals",
B: "parent rock",
C: "decaying plants",
D: "root nodules",
answer: "B. parent rock",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. One reason for brushing the teeth regularly is to",
A: "reduce the amount of saliva in the mouth",
B: "remove dead cheek cells from the mouth",
C: "dilute the alkali content",
D: "reduce bacterial activity in the mouth",
answer: "D. reduce bacterial activity in the mouth",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. A converging lens can be used as magnifying glass, only when the object is placed",
A: "at the focal point",
B: "between the focal point and a distance twice the focal point",
C: "between the focal point and the optical centre",
D: "at a distance twice the focal length",
answer: "C. between the focal point and the optical centre",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. Heavy traffic in cities causes \nI. air pollution \nII. noise pollution \nIII. hindrance to fast movement",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. Which of the following compounds represents an alkanol?",
A: "CH3COH",
B: "CH3COOH",
C: "CH3CH2OH",
D: "CH3COCH3",
answer: "C. CH3CH2OH",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Kinetic and potential energies are known collectively as",
A: "chemical energy",
B: "gravitational energy",
C: "mechanical energy",
D: "renewable energy",
answer: "C. mechanical energy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. An element A has two electrons in its outer shell. Another element B has six electrons in its outer shell. The most likely compound which can be formed by the combination of the two elements is",
A: "AB",
B: "AB2",
C: "A2B",
D: "A2B2",
answer: "A. AB",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. Which of the following structures controls the passage of dissolved substances in and out of living cells?",
A: "cell membrane",
B: "Cytoplasm",
C: "Golgi bodies",
D: "Nucleus",
answer: "A. cell membrane",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. Pollution by carbon monoxide can be minimized by",
A: "effective burning of fuel",
B: "incomplete burning of fuel",
C: "using firewood as fuel",
D: "using petrol as fuel",
answer: "A. effective burning of fuel",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. Which of the following diseases is correctly matched with the animal it infects?",
A: "Rinderpest → chicken",
B: "Trypanosomiasis → cattle",
C: "Aspergillosis → pig",
D: "Anthrax → turkey",
answer: "B. Trypanosomiasis → cattle",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. The advantages of family planning does not include",
A: "giving each child enough attention",
B: "reducing pressure on social amenities",
C: "preserving the health of the mother",
D: "choosing the sex of children to be born",
answer: "D. choosing the sex of children to be born",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Which of the following statements about non-dehiscent fruits is true?",
A: "their walls dry at maturity",
B: "their seeds are dispersed by wind",
C: "they contain numerous seeds",
D: "they do not split open when mature",
answer: "D. they do not split open when mature",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. A machine has a velocity ratio of 9 and needs an effort of 10 N to lift a load of 50 N. Calculate the efficiency of the machine.",
A: "5%",
B: "45%",
C: "55%",
D: "90%",
answer: "C. 55%",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. The breakdown of cellulose by bacteria in ruminants occurs in the",
A: "abomasum",
B: "Amsum",
C: "reticulum",
D: "Rumen",
answer: "D. Rumen",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. A student performed an experiment to determine the percentage of air in a soil sample. The following were the readings: volume of water in measuring cylinder = 500cm3, volume of the soil added to water = 350cm3, volume of soil and water after stirring = 800cm3. What is the percentage of air in the soil?",
A: "6.25%",
B: "10.36%",
C: "14.28%",
D: "62.50%",
answer: "A. 6",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. In computer language, data can be defined as",
A: "raw facts that are fed into the computer",
B: "important business decisions stored on the computer",
C: "symbols and letters used in the computer",
D: "programs on a floppy disk",
answer: "A. raw facts that are fed into the computer",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. A body of mass 100.0 kg moves with a velocity of 8.0 ms−1. Calculate its kinetic energy",
A: "400.0 J",
B: "800.0 J",
C: "3200.0 J",
D: "4000.0 J",
answer: "C. 3200",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. Which of the following characteristics is discontinuous variation?",
A: "blood group of patients in a hospital",
B: "complexion of members of a church",
C: "height of pupils in a class",
D: "weight of athletes in a team",
answer: "A. blood group of patients in a hospital",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. The quantity of heat contained in a body does not depend on the",
A: "density of the body",
B: "mass of the body",
C: "temperature of the body",
D: "volume of the body",
answer: "D. volume of the body",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. Female circumcision comes with all the following dangers except",
A: "development of frigidity.",
B: "excessive loss of blood",
C: "getting infected with diseases",
D: "having children with reduced intelligence",
answer: "D. having children with reduced intelligence",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. Which of the following processes is a physical process?",
A: "electrolysis",
B: "evaporation",
C: "photosynthesis",
D: "respiration",
answer: "B. evaporation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. The following are all methods of maintaining sanitation in the community except",
A: "clearing of gutters",
B: "draining of stagnant waters",
C: "fitting of mosquito nets to houses",
D: "weeding around houses",
answer: "C. fitting of mosquito nets to houses",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. A body of mass of 40.0 kg climbs a wall 2.0m high. What is the work done against gravity if g=10.0ms-2",
A: "80.0 J",
B: "160.0 J",
C: "200.0 J",
D: "800.0 J",
answer: "D. 800",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. One reason why the spinal cord is enclosed in the neural canal is because",
A: "it is delicate",
B: "it is located at the back of the body",
C: "its distribution in the body must be restricted",
D: "it is an extension of brain",
answer: "A. it is delicate",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. Which of the following tools is an example of a second class lever?",
A: "a claw hammer",
B: "a pair of tongs",
C: "a pair of scissors",
D: "a wheelbarrow",
answer: "D. a wheelbarrow",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. During exhalation, air is forced out of the lungs because",
A: "the concentration of carbon dioxide is higher within the lungs",
B: "pressure in the lungs is increased",
C: "the muscles of the diaphragm contract",
D: "the rib cage is raised upwards",
answer: "B. pressure in the lungs is increased",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. An electric kettle is rated 2000W, 240V. Which of the following fuse ratings will you recommend for the kettle?",
A: "5.0A",
B: "8.3A",
C: "13.0A",
D: "15.0A",
answer: "B. 8",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Which of the following ornamental plants is propagated by seed?",
A: "Croton",
B: "Ice plant",
C: "Milk bush",
D: "Red Ixora C",
answer: "C. Milk bush",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. To increase the stability of a body, the",
A: "body must be made heavier",
B: "height and base length of the body must be increased",
C: "base length must be increased",
D: "height of the body must reduced and the base length increased",
answer: "D. height of the body must reduced and the base length increased",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. The ability of the human body to resist infection by producing antibodies is known as",
A: "immunity",
B: "Phagocytosis",
C: "mitosis",
D: "mutation",
answer: "A. immunity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Ectoparasites in poultry are controlled by",
A: "dusting birds with chemicals",
B: "feeding birds with balanced ration",
C: "mixing drugs in feed",
D: "vaccinating birds with recommended drugs",
answer: "A. dusting birds with chemicals",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. An object is placed 50cm from a converging lens of focal length 15cm. The image formed is",
A: "real, inverted and diminished",
B: "real, inverted and magnified",
C: "real, inverted and same size as object",
D: "virtual, upright and magnified",
answer: "B. real, inverted and magnified",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Which of the following processes is an application of latent heat?",
A: "cooling water in a refrigerator",
B: "evaporation of sweat on the body",
C: "heating a bi-metallic strip",
D: "warming up water",
answer: "B. evaporation of sweat on the body",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. Food substances can be prevented from growing mouldy by  \nI. adding sugar \nII. pickling \nIII. Salting \nIV. drying",
A: "I,II and III only",
B: "I, III and IV only",
C: "II, III and IV only",
D: "I ,II ,III and IV",
answer: "D. I ,II ,III and IV",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Which of the following statements about fertilization in humans is true?",
A: "only one egg is fertilized at a time",
B: "it can occur at any time",
C: "many sperms fertilize the ovum",
D: "it always occurs inside the female A",
answer: "A. only one egg is fertilized at a time",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. The best period to harvest fodder for preparing silage or hay is",
A: "the flowering stage",
B: "the flower drop stage",
C: "before flowering",
D: "after flowering",
answer: "C. before flowering",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. In the wiring of houses, appliances are connected in parallel to enable",
A: "each appliance have the same voltage",
B: "power to be saved",
C: "each appliance have the same current",
D: "the power to be stepped up",
answer: "A. each appliance have the same voltage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. It is advisable to place windows of a room opposite each other in order to",
A: "have a wider field of view",
B: "allow fresh air to move through the room",
C: "create a humid condition in the room",
D: "allow enough sunshine into the room",
answer: "B. allow fresh air to move through the room",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Which of the following processes can be described as an indigenous technology?",
A: "Batik making",
B: "crude oil extraction",
C: "fertilizer application",
D: "Shea butter extraction",
answer: "D. Shea butter extraction",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. The left ventricle of the heart has the thickest wall because",
A: "it is the largest chamber of the heart",
B: "it requires much pressure to pump blood to the heart",
C: "the blood, which gets into the left ventricle is under low pressure",
D: "the left ventricle has to pump blood to all parts of the body",
answer: "B. it requires much pressure to pump blood to the heart",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. The best procedure of applying irrigation to crops is to",
A: "supply just the amount the crop requires",
B: "mulch before watering",
C: "water crops everyday",
D: "water anytime it does not rain",
answer: "C. water crops everyday",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. When a female animal is crossed with its own offspring the process is described as",
A: "artificial insemination",
B: "Inbreeding",
C: "natural breeding",
D: "out-crossing",
answer: "B. Inbreeding",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. If one bird can lay 250 eggs per year, determine the number of birds that can lay 840,000 eggs per year",
A: "280",
B: "2,800",
C: "2,976",
D: "3,360",
answer: "D. 3,360",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. Which of the following chemical formulae correctly represents aluminum tetraoxosulphate (VI)?",
A: "Al(SO4)2",
B: "Al2SO4",
C: "Al2(SO4)3",
D: "Al3(SO4)2",
answer: "B. Al2SO4",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. Copper, silver and gold are able to resist corrosion and are therefore suitable for making",
A: "alloys",
B: "coins",
C: "engine blocks",
D: "paints",
answer: "A. alloys",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. Biological control of malaria involves",
A: "draining breeding grounds of mosquitoes",
B: "spraying dieldrin onto surfaces where mosquitoes settle",
C: "introducing fish into ponds to feed on larvae and pupae of mosquitoes",
D: "burying all empty tins",
answer: "C. introducing fish into ponds to feed on larvae and pupae of mosquitoes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. Which of the following processes is used in the purification of water for town supply?",
A: "Addition of alum to quicken the rate of sedimentation",
B: "Exposure to air to increase oxygen content of water",
C: "Filtration to remove micro-organisms",
D: "Pumping of water from the water station",
answer: "A. Addition of alum to quicken the rate of sedimentation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. Personal hygiene involves \nI. brushing the teeth regularly \nII. cutting the nails \nIII. Combing the hair \nIV. sweeping the compound",
A: "I, II and III only",
B: "I,II and IV only",
C: "I,III and IV only",
D: "I, II,III,and IV",
answer: "A. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question51",
question: "51. Which of the following ranks of organisms will have more closely related characteristics?",
A: "Class",
B: "Family",
C: "Genus",
D: "Order",
answer: "C. Genus",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question52",
question: "52. Anaemia in cattle is likely to result from attack by",
A: "roundworms",
B: "Tapeworms",
C: "ticks",
D: "trypanosoma",
answer: "C. ticks",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question53",
question: "53. The degree of soil erosion is not affected by the",
A: "amount of rainfall",
B: "leaching of soil nutrients",
C: "amount of vegetation cover on the soil",
D: "physical nature of the soil",
answer: "B. leaching of soil nutrients",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question54",
question: "54. Which of the following statements about a bucket of water and a cup of water both 100°C is true?",
A: "The cup of water contains more heat energy than the water in the bucket.",
B: "The bucket of water will heat faster",
C: "Both of them have the same amount of heat energy",
D: "The bucket of water contains more heat energy than the cup of water",
answer: "D. The bucket of water contains more heat energy than the cup of water",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question55",
question: "55. A helium nucleus has two protons. How many electrons must be present in its shell to make it a neutral atom?",
A: "−4",
B: "−2",
C: "+2",
D: "+4",
answer: "C. +2",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question56",
question: "56. Which of the following cultural practices help to conserve the forest?",
A: "cover cropping",
B: "crop rotation",
C: "mechanized farming",
D: "shifting cultivation",
answer: "A. cover cropping",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question57",
question: "57. The following are all physical properties of matter except",
A: "capillarity",
B: "Heat",
C: "Viscosity",
D: "volume",
answer: "B. Heat",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question58",
question: "58. Medulla oblongata is part of the",
A: "fore-brain",
B: "hind-brain",
C: "mid-brain",
D: "spinal cord",
answer: "B. hind-brain",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question59",
question: "59. Plant diseases across borders are prevented and controlled by",
A: "education",
B: "cross breeding",
C: "Inoculation",
D: "Quarantining",
answer: "D. Quarantining",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question60",
question: "60. Which of the following properties is not a feature of a secondary cell?",
A: "it produces an alternating current",
B: "it can be recharged",
C: "it lasts longer than a primary cell",
D: "it can be used for heavy duty purposes.",
answer: "A. it produces an alternating current",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},



]